It's me. I know you can 't stand to see me.
喂 是我 我知道你不想跟我共處一室
I'm trying to apologize over the phone
我想用電話跟你道歉…
I shouldn't have kissed your girlfriend
我不該親你的女朋友…
Stop calling!
別再打來了
This is 92.3 WXRK,K-Rock...
這裡是92.3搖滾廣播電台
...calling with our $ 1000 daily challenge!
您是今天的千元挑戰者
All right!
漂亮
What is the name of...
請問...
...your roommate who is very sorry and would do anything?
你那位非常抱歉 願意盡全力…
-Damn it,Chandler,stop calling. -Joey,it's Ross.
錢德，別再打來了 喬伊，我是羅斯
-Sorry. -It's all right.
對不起 沒關係
What's up?
什麼事？
Not much. I got Chandler here and he's really,really sorry
也沒什麼 錢德在我這邊，他非常非常…
The One with Chandler in a Box
本集播出：閉關思過
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Oh,turkey!
火雞…
Giving thanks!
說謝謝
Look,everyone. It's the spirit of Thanksgiving!
看，這就是感恩節的精神
Are things with Joey better?
你跟喬伊好一點了嗎？
They couldn't be worse. I spent eight hours calling him...
糟到不能再糟 我昨晚打了8小時電話給他
...trying to get him to talk to me.
想讓他跟我說上一句話
Eight hours.
8小時
You could probably use a plug-in telephone headset.
你應該用得上耳機吧？
Should we all expect Christmas gifts that are stolen from your office?
我們會收到 你從公司偷來的聖誕禮物嗎？
You shouldn't.
你不會
Speaking of Christmas....
講到聖誕節
Since Monica and I are starting a new business and have no money...
摩妮卡和我剛開業，沒有錢
...this year we could do Secret Santa and each only buy one gift.
今年就來抽籤互送吧 這樣只要買一份禮物
And there's the added mystery of who gets who.
還可以猜猜看誰抽到誰
Who gets whom.
誰抽到「哪個人」
I don't know why I do that.
我是無意識的
But it is correct.
但那樣才合文法
Hey,what's this? It's all of your names.
這是什麼？ 是你們的名字！
Let's pick.
來抽吧
Hey,what's going?
你們在…
-No,Joey,stay. -We're picking names for Secret Santa.
喬伊，不要走 我們要抽籤送禮
Okay.
好啦
I invented Secret Santa,you know.
這個做法是我發明的
What are you laughing at? You're the one who said Die Hard was your idea.
你笑什麼？ 你也說「終極警探」 是你的構想
It was.
本來就是
Don't make me show you the napkin.
別逼我把紙巾拿出來
I'm going to take a nap. Turkey makes me sleepy.
我要去睡個覺，火雞讓我愛睏
We haven't eaten yet.
還沒吃耶
I know,but all that work you're doing to get it ready and....
我知道，但你那堆準備過程…
Did you pick Rachel for your Secret Santa? I'll trade for her.
你們有人抽到瑞秋嗎？我要換
I picked her. Thank God,you want her!
我抽到她，幸好你要她
Why do you want to get rid of her so badly?
你為什麼這麼想換掉她？
She exchanges every gift she gets.
因為她收到什麼都拿去換
It's impossible to get her something she likes.
要讓她滿意根本不可能
Come on,let's trade!
來換吧
I got her that backpack and she loved it.
哪有這回事 她很喜歡我送她的背包
I remember she cried when that big dog ran off with
有只大狗把它叼走時 她哭得好…
There was no big dog.
沒有什麼大狗
This sucks! I already got her a briefcase with "R.G." put on it.
真是的，我已經買了個公事包 還拿去燙了RG
Her initials.
她的姓名縮寫
Okay,I'm really bad at initials.
我很不會認縮寫
You got your shopping done early.
你今年禮物買得真早
Yeah,well,my Camel Cash was about to expire.
我的禮券快過期了
Maybe you can give it to somebody else. Like Ross Geller!
也許你可以送給別人 像羅斯蓋勒（縮寫亦為RG）
You know what? It's a girlie briefcase.
那是個女用公事包
Who cares! He works in a museum.
那又怎樣，他在博物館上班
The big game's about to start!
現在幾點？球賽要開始了
Ross and Joey aren't here. You can watch the parade if you want.
羅斯喬伊不在，你可以看遊行
Thanks.
謝了
What is wrong with this freezer?
這個冷凍庫怎麼搞的
-What happened? -lce just got in my eye!
怎麼了？ 我的眼睛被冰扎到
People are trying to sleep in here!
這裡有人要睡覺
Monica got ice in her eye and it hurts!
摩妮卡的眼睛被冰扎到很痛
-Open it up. Let me see. -I can't. It really kills.
張開讓我看看 不行，真的很痛
Maybe you should put some ice on it.
也許你應該冰敷
-lt looks bad. -We should take you to a doctor.
好像很嚴重 去看醫生好了
No,my eye doctor is Richard!
不行，我的眼科醫生是理查
I can't go to him when I don't have a boyfriend.
我沒有男朋友不能去見他
He's really picky about his patients.
他對病患還真挑剔
You've got to go. What's his office number?
你非去不可 他的診所電話幾號？
Like I remember his office number!
我哪會記得
Speed dial seven.
速撥鍵七
I'm calling on behalf of Monica Geller's eye.
喂，我代表摩妮卡蓋勒的眼睛
Is Richard Burke in today?
理查柏克今天在嗎？
He's not in. Will she see the on-call doctor?
他不在，她願意看候診醫師嗎
-Yes. -She's very excited about that!
願意！ 願意！她非常興奮
Okay,we'll be right in.
好，我們馬上過去
Okay,so who's gonna take her in?
誰要帶她去？
I'll go,you can watch your parade.
我來，你去看遊行
It's so cool. Till Monica gets back,I'm head chef.
酷斃了 摩妮卡回來之前，我是主廚
And I get to make all the decisions.
我可以做決定
She told you to follow the recipe exactly.
她叫你完全照食譜來
Get out of my kitchen.
滾出我的廚房
I think I'm making some progress with Joey.
好，我跟喬伊有進展了
When I walked in, he went to his bedroom...
我進門時，他走進他的房間
...but he only slammed the door once.
但只摔了一次門
Yeah,he gave me the finger while doing it.
不過摔的時候有比中指
I've got to call my mom and ask her a left-handed cooking question.
我得問我媽左手烹飪的問題
I'm gonna be in there.
我要進房裡去
While I'm gone....
我不在的時候…
Chandler,you're in charge.
錢德，你負責
I picked Monica for Secret Santa,but I'm getting her something for Hanukkah.
我抽到摩妮卡 但我已經替她買了光明節禮物
You want to switch?
你想換嗎？
I was trying to trade...
其實我想換成...
...for you.
...你
Really? That's so nice. What are you getting me?
真的？真好，你要送我什麼？
I don't know,R.G. I was thinking something girlie for your office.
不曉得，RG 某種女性化的上班用品吧
Maybe Phoebe will switch with me.
也許菲比會跟我換
Then you'll get stuck with Rachel, and she exchanges every gift.
最好不要，那你會抽到瑞秋 她什麼禮物都拿去換
No,I got her lots of stuff she never took back.
亂講 我送她很多東西她都沒退
Like?
比如？
Like that gold necklace I got her last year.
像我去年送她的金項鏈
When did she wear it last?
她上次戴是哪時？
She wore it all Christmas day and then....
她聖誕節整天都戴著，然後…
Big dog?
大狗？
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Sending back this stuff Chandler bought.
把錢德因內疚買的東西退回去
-Even the TV? -No,I'll put that in my room.
全部？包括電視？ 不，電視要搬進房裡
Listen,Joey. I know what he did was wrong.
喬伊，我知道他做錯了
But can't you hear him out?
但你就不能聽他解釋嗎？
If Chandler had kissed Rachel, would you hear him out?
你和瑞秋在一起的時候， 如果錢德吻了瑞秋，你會聽他解釋麼
That's a good point.
說得好
How long you going to punish him?
那你要罰他多久？
Five years.
5年
You've sentenced him?
你還判了刑？
Don't do the crime if you can't do the time.
不敢當就不要做
The guy's your best friend.
他是你最要好的朋友
Was my best friend.
曾經是我最好的朋友
I don't know why you're pushing for him.
你幹嘛拚命替他說情？
With him out of the way as my best friend,there's a spot open.
少了他礙事 我就沒有最要好的朋友了
-Who,me? -Yeah.
我嗎？ 對
I'm honored. You know what I'm going to do as your best friend?
我真榮幸 你知道我首先要做什麼？
I'm going to get you to talk to Chandler.
拉你去跟錢德說話
All right.
好啦
But if you weren't my best friend....
若非你是我最好的朋友…
Oh,my God. Is it really that bad?
天哪，真的那麼嚴重？
I walk in the room, and he won't talk to me.
我進了門，他根本不理我
He just mumbles something in ltalian.
只念了幾句意大利文
And I know he only knows the bad words.
我知道他只會髒話
I'm so,so sorry. I feel responsible.
真對不起，都是我不好
It's not your fault.
不是你的錯
-Gunther,have you seen Chandler? -I thought you were Chandler.
阿甘，你有看見錢德嗎？ 我以為你才是錢德
But one of you is over there.
你們其中一個在那邊
Hey,Joe.
喬伊
（意大利文）
I'll be right with you. Thanks for coming in.
我馬上就好 謝謝你
Oh,my God! How cute is the on-call doctor?
天哪，這個候診醫生真帥
So cute that I'm thinking about jamming this pen in my eye.
帥到我想拿筆插我的眼睛
-You have the best luck with eye doctors. -I know.
你的眼科醫生緣真好 我知道
Dr. Burke will see you now.
柏克醫生可以見你了
Not Dr. Burke. The on-call doctor will see me now.
不是柏克醫生，柏克醫生不在 是候診醫生要幫我看
Dr. Richard Burke is out.
理查柏克醫生不在
Dr. Timothy Burke,his son, will see you now.
他兒子提摩西柏克醫生幫你看
Ready?
準備好了嗎？
Hey,I'm sorry. That
對不起，剛才…
-Where you going? -My folks'.
你要去哪裡？ 我爸媽家
When you coming back?
什麼時候回來？
I don't know. I might stay there while I look for an apartment.
不知道 可能會住幾天順便找房子
What?
什麼？
I thought we could talk about this. Work it out.
原先我以為我們可以談開來
Seeing you two together,I don't....
但是看到你們在一起…
What do you want me to say? Should I stop seeing her?
你要我說什麼？ 說我不見她嗎？
It's not about her. Okay?
跟她無關，好嗎？
But seeing you together reminds me of what you did.
但看到你們在一起 就讓我想起你做的事
I won't live with someone who doesn't know what it is to be a friend.
我不跟一個不懂朋友道義的人 住在一起
I know what it is to be a friend. I screwed up.
我懂朋友道義，只是我搞砸了
Yeah,you did.
對，沒錯
And that's why I'm leaving.
所以我要離開
If you're not going to stay for me, then at least stay for them.
你不為我留下來 至少為它們留下來
They had a very difficult year. What with the robbery and all.
它們這1年很不順，還被搶
And that chick used to be very cute.
小雞本來很可愛的
When that guy was robbing us...
當那個人搶了我們
...and I was locked in the entertainment unit for six hours...
我在櫃子裡關了6小時
...do you know what I was doing?
你知道我在做什麼？
I was thinking about how I let you down.
我在想我太讓你失望了
If I knew what kind of friend you'd be,I wouldn't have worried.
對，早知道你會見色忘友 我根本不會擔心
Wait one second! There has to be something that I can do.
等一下…一定有什麼我能做的
If we still had that unit...
如果櫃子還在
...I'd get in it for six hours and think about how I let you down.
我會關6小時 檢討我有多讓你失望
What?
We got a box.
我們有一個箱子
I remember the last time I saw you.
我記得上次見到你
It was the morning I left for college.
是去外地唸書的早上
You were standing outside the Dairy Queen.
你站在乳品店外面
Just probably waiting for it to open.
八成是在等它開店
-You look great now. -You look great too.
你現在好漂亮 你也很帥
You're an excellent patient.
你真是個好病人
How does it look?
情況如何？
You have a scratch on your cornea. You have to wear a patch.
你的角膜有刮傷 得戴幾天眼罩
Like a pirate?
像海盜那樣？
If that helps you.
你懂就好
How long have you been working with your dad?
你跟著你爸多久了？
Come on,one of us had to mention him.
總得有人提到他
I moved back here a couple months ago.
我是2個月前搬回來的
Big family dinner tonight?
晚上要家庭聚餐？
No way!
不會吧
I was gonna have Thanksgiving at my girlfriend's.
我本來要去女朋友家吃飯
But we broke up.
但我們分手了
She wasn't ready for a serious commitment.
她還不想定下來
So you made her walk the plank, aye,matey?
所以你讓她跳海吃自己？
You're not wearing the patch yet.
你還沒戴眼罩呢
I know.
我知道
-He's coming here for Thanksgiving? -I know. It's sick.
他要來過感恩節？ 對啊，好變態喔
-Why is it sick? -It's Richard's son!
為什麼變態？ 因為他是理查的兒子
It's like inviting a Greek tragedy over for dinner.
這跟找希臘悲劇來吃飯一樣
If it were Greek, I'd be blind in both eyes.
希臘人會把兩隻眼睛都蒙住
I like him because he's handsome and he's nice and smart and handsome.
我喜歡他的英俊、體帖 聰明和…英俊
Phoebe,you understand,don't you?
菲比，你瞭解吧？
I could see where I'd be your best shot,but no.
我知道你為什麼指望我 但是不行
Sorry,honey. I think it's twisted.
對不起，我覺得很畸形
-What's twisted? -Me going out with Richard's son.
什麼事畸形？ 我跟理查的兒子交往
好惡！
惡惡惡
It sounds like a really bad idea to me.
我覺得實在不太好
-ls he okay in there? -He's fine!
他這樣可以嗎？ 他好得很
If things work out between you and Richard's son...
要是你跟理查的兒子有結果
...you can tell your kids...
你就可以告訴孩子
...that you slept with their grandfather.
你跟他們的爺爺上過床
Judge all you want to.
隨你們怎麼批評
Married a lesbian, left a man at the altar...
娶到女同志，臨陣逃婚
...Ioved a gay ice dancer...
愛上同性戀冰上舞者
...threw a girl's wooden leg in the fire,live in a box!
把女生的木腿丟進火裡 睡在箱子裡
What exactly is the point of the box?
睡箱子的用意到底何在？ 錢德
The meaning of the box is threefold.
有三重意義
One,it gives me the time to think about what I did.
第一，讓我有時間反省
Two,it proves how much I care about my friendship with Joey.
第二，證明我有多重視 跟喬伊的友誼
And three...
第三…
...it hurts.
會痛
And if he stays in the box you guys will be friends again?
他關在裡面，你們就能和好？
Let's just say it's a start.
這是個開始
Remember that necklace I gave you last year?
記得我去年送你的項鏈嗎？
Can I see it?
可以給我看嗎？
Why?
為什麼？
I just want to check something.
我只是想看一下
Okay.
好
Now we'll see.
等著瞧吧
Air hole! Air hole!
沒氣了！沒氣了
Here it is. I love it. I wear it all the time.
在這裡，我很喜歡，我常戴
The necklace I got you was gold. This is silver.
我送的是金項鏈，這是銀的
Well,maybe...
也許它…
...it changed.
變色了
Oh,my God! You actually exchanged it.
天哪，你真的拿去換
Isn't it better to exchange it for something I enjoy...
換一個我喜歡又常用的東西
...and can use a lot?
不是比較好？
What did you get?
你換了什麼？
Credit.
換購金額
I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it.
我來開我來開…
Hi,Tim.
提姆
Thank you. Come meet my friends.
謝謝，來見我的朋友
Phoebe.
這是菲比 幸會
And Joey.
喬伊 你好
My brother,Ross.
我哥哥羅斯 你好
And Rachel.
還有瑞秋
That's Chandler.
那是錢德
How do you do?
你好
-What's? -Well,he's....
這是… 他在…
He's doing some thinking.
他在反省
-What happened? -You kissed my girlfriend!
怎麼了？ 你親了我的女朋友
I like those sunglasses.
我喜歡那個墨鏡
"Like them" like them? Or "I'd like to get store credit" like them?
是喜歡的喜歡 還是可以換成換購金額的喜歡
（意大利文）
This turkey is ready.
各位，火雞上桌了
Where can I wash up?
哪裡可以洗手？
Let me show you.
來…我帶你去
The towels are hanging next to the sink.
毛巾掛在洗手台旁邊
-And you can use the fancy soap. -Thank you.
你可以用高級香皂 謝謝
Fancy soap? I thought we were saving that for the pope.
高級香皂？ 我以為要留給教宗用
See. He's nice,right?
他人很好吧？
Do you want a relationship where you can actually say:
但你真的想在談戀愛時說
"That's not how your dad used to do it"?
「你爸的做法不同」？
Everything looks great. Where should I sit?
看起來好好吃，我坐哪裡？
Saved you a seat.
我幫你留了
Sick,sick,sick,sick.
變態變態變態變態
I'll get it.
我去開
Got you!
被我騙了
That doesn't sound like thinking to me.
這聽起來不像是反省
-Sorry! -You shouldn't be talking at all.
對不起 你不應該說話
You've got too much thinking to do to be talking and joking.
你要想的太多了 不該說話開玩笑
Okay,you got it!
好，沒問題
Ross,pass me the yams?
羅斯，把蕃薯給我
Joey's got the mashed potatoes if you want to exchange them.
好，你想換的話 喬伊那裡有馬鈴薯泥
Will you stop! What's the matter with you?
夠了，你是怎麼搞的？
We've got company.
有客人喔
Nothing's the matter with me.
我沒怎麼搞的
I'm not completely devoid of sentiment. I have feelings.
我不是麻木不仁的人 我也有感覺
Okay,fine.
好，很好
You can't tell,but I'm breaking the tension by mooning you guys.
你們看不到 但我正在露屁股打圓場
All right,look!
聽著
If this is a big joke to you, forget about it.
如果你把它當成笑話 那就算了
This means something to me.
這對我很重要
If it doesn't mean anything to you, then get out of there.
要是對你不重要，你就死出來
Otherwise,you're just an idiot in a box.
否則就太白癡了
You're right. I'm sorry. This means a lot to me.
你說得對，對不起 這對我非常重要
I want to be friends again. I swear I won't say another word.
我想跟你和解 我發誓不會再說話了
-So you'll take this seriously? -Absolutely!
你會當一回事？ 絕對會
That sounds like another word to me.
你又說話羅
Are you going to take this seriously?
你會當一回事嗎？
Okay!
很好
Don't say that I have no sentiment.
別說我麻木不仁
This is a movie stub from our first date.
這是第一次約會的電影票根
This eggshell is from the first time you made me breakfast in bed.
這是你第一次 為我做床上早餐的蛋殼
This is from the museum, the first time we...
這是博物館的，我們第一次…
...were together.
在一起
Maybe I exchange gifts sometimes, but I keep the things that matter.
我有時會換禮物 但重要的東西我會留
I don't know what to say. I'm sorry.
我不知道該說什麼，對不起
Though you're not supposed to take these.
但是…這個不能拿
It's,like,a million years old.
它有百萬年的歷史
We actually have people looking for that.
我們還得派專人去挖
-Mind if I smoke? -Care if I die?
我可以抽煙嗎？ 想害死我嗎？
No,I'm just kidding,I'm just kidding. Go ahead,smoke.
開玩笑的，你抽吧
This always happens.
老是會卡住
Here,let me.
讓我來
Thank you.
謝謝
You have very beautiful...
你有很漂亮的...
...eye.
..眼睛
My friends think this is weird.
我朋友都覺得這樣很怪
Even the one in the box?
包括箱子裡那個？
It's not weird,is it?
這樣不會很怪吧？
I thought it would be. I almost canceled,but it really isn't.
我原先也覺得會，還差點取消 但其實不會
I know. Me and your dad, that's totally separate.
我知道 我跟你爸完全是兩回事
I totally agree.
我完全同意
We're two people who find each other...
我們只是兩個…
...very attractive.
...互相吸引的人
Right?
對吧？
-What? -Nothing,nothing.
怎麼了？ 沒事
No,really. Was that not okay?
那個吻不好嗎？
No,that was good.
不，很好
That was a good kiss.
那個吻很好
-lt reminded you of -Don't say it!
天哪！它讓你想到… 別說
-lt did,didn't it? -Yes!
但是有，對吧？ 對！
I know!
天哪！ 我知道
God,I am sorry. I am so sorry.
對不起，我真的很抱歉
It's okay. It wouldn't be Thanksgiving without a little emotional scarring.
沒關係 少了感情瘡疤就不叫感恩節
You know what's even worse?
更糟的是...
My friends were right.
我朋友說得對
You know what's worst for me is you remind me of a younger version of my mom.
最糟的是 我覺得你就像年輕的我媽
-I want you to know how sorry I am -It's okay.
聽著，我真的很抱歉… 沒關係
-Chandler's the one I'm mad at. -Well,I'm still sorry.
我氣的是錢德 我還是很抱歉
-ls he here? -ln the box.
他在嗎？ 在箱子裡
He can't talk right now.
錢德？ 他現在不能說話
Why not? What's going on?
為什麼？怎麼了？
He's trying to show Joey how much he means to him.
他想表示他很重視喬伊
-By being in a box? -Joey had reasons.
所以窩在箱子裡？ 喬伊有他的理由
They were threefold.
有三重意義
You not being able to talk might make this easier.
你不能說話反而讓事情好辦
Listen....
聽我說…
I don't want to be someone who comes between two best friends.
聽我說 我不想介入兩個最要好的朋友
I can't stand seeing what this is doing to you guys.
我不忍心看著這件事影響你們
And I don't want to be the cause of that.
我不想成為罪魁禍首
I don't think we can see each other anymore.
所以我們不該再見面了
I'm going to my mom's in Chicago.
我要去芝加哥找我媽
I'm going to stay there for a while.
我會住一陣子
I think this could have been something really amazing.
這段感情本來會很美好
But,you know,this is probably for the best.
但這麼做最好
You know?
你懂嗎？
I'm going to miss you.
我會想你的
Goodbye,Chandler.
別了，錢德
Open the box!
把箱子打開啦
What?
什麼？
He can still catch her. Get out of there! Get out of there!
他還追得上她，快出來啦
We're going to be fine. Get out!
所以… 我們沒事啦，出來啦
You did some real good thinking in there.
真的？ 對，你好好反省過了
I mean,this is....
這真是…
You could still catch her!
快，你還追得上她
And merry Christmas from your Secret Santa!
神秘聖誕老人祝你聖誕快樂
All right,who got Chandler? Because I need to trade.
誰抽到錢德？我要換
He sees her!
他看到她了
He's catching up to her.
他在追她
She sees him!
她看到他了
They're hugging!
他們擁抱了
He's taking her purse.
他在搶她的皮包
That's not them.
那不是他們
I'll go call the police.
我去報警
There they are!
他們在那裡
All right,get a room.
快去開房間吧